<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kate Bagoy</title>
    <description>I  transform ideas into beautiful, user-focused  designs</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 18:52:36 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 18:52:36 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Three benefits of studying business</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Studying business may sound intimidating, but the skills that you’ll develop along the way can be life-changing. A business course will teach you things that give you massive advantages as you navigate your way through your professional life in the years to come. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such an integral part of society, businesses are seeking innovative and knowledgeable individuals to help them stay on the cutting edge of this fast-paced industry – and they’re willing to pay well for it, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help you decide if a business course is right for you, let’s explore three key benefits of studying business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;transferable-skills&quot;&gt;Transferable skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you progress through a business course or degree, you’ll develop many high-value skills that are in high demand worldwide. The practical side of &lt;a href=&quot;https://universitycompare.com/courses/undergraduate?s=business&quot;&gt;learning business management&lt;/a&gt; will teach you how to skillfully manage finances, and you’ll develop excellent numeracy skills, learn marketing and budgeting strategies, and gain strong decision-making skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, you’ll grow your soft skills, and likely end up with excellent communication, negotiation and presentation abilities. All of these skills are highly valued and transferable to any industry, so even if you don’t pursue a career in business after your course, you’ll walk into any other job at a much higher level. This can open up career opportunities across many sectors and industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;good-financial-prospects&quot;&gt;Good financial prospects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we’ve touched on, having a keen set of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/bernardmarr/2022/08/22/the-top-10-most-in-demand-skills-for-the-next-10-years/&quot;&gt;highly valued skills&lt;/a&gt; will put you in good stead for taking home a decent paycheck in any industry. But working in the business sector typically returns better financial rewards than other sectors for your time and efforts.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If living a lavish lifestyle and enjoying a premium work-life balance are high on your priority list, then a business degree may be the best option for you. Also, a business degree will enable you to job-hunt worldwide, as businesses globally are constantly seeking fresh expertise and knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;opportunity-to-specialize&quot;&gt;Opportunity to specialize&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During a business course you’ll gain a broad understanding of how a business is built, how it operates and what keeps it in the green. You can then choose to specialize in a specific area to take your expertise to the next level, which is particularly important for anyone looking to start up their own company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a business degree, there are lots of different modules that could support you in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.indeed.com/career-advice/career-development/degree-needed-to-open-your-own-business&quot;&gt;setting up and managing your own business&lt;/a&gt;. From understanding management procedures and policies to developing vital interview skills, research processes and operation tactics, learning these essential business skills will open up global possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pave-the-way-to-being-your-own-boss&quot;&gt;Pave the way to being your own boss&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those with hopes of financial freedom and being your own boss, studying a business course is a great place to start. If you fancy yourself as an entrepreneur, gaining inside knowledge of the industry is sure to make starting your own business much easier and increase your chances of being successful. Plus, with the hands-on approach of many business courses, you’re sure to build a network of business-minded people who can help springboard you into making your career dreams a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@kyledevaras?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=unsplash&quot;&gt;Kyle Gregory Devaras&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/6RTM8EsD1T8?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=unsplash&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/benefits-of-studying-business/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/benefits-of-studying-business/</guid>
        
        
        <category>marketing-tips</category>
        
        <category>general</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Three AI tools for freelancers, that&apos;ll help you work smarter</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;AI is revolutionising the world of business. Industries of all different descriptions are capitalising on the latest advancements that are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/boosting-productivity-ai-how-artificial-intelligence-changing-jean/&quot;&gt;helping to boost productivity&lt;/a&gt; and efficiency in so many different ways. But as a freelancer, it’s unlikely that you’ll receive any kind of formal training with these tools, so it can be difficult to know what AI can do for you and just how to optimise your use of it. In this guide, we explore three ways in which you can leverage artificial intelligence to help you optimise your time and streamline your workflow as a freelancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;automating-repetitive-tasks&quot;&gt;Automating repetitive tasks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a freelancer, you’ll be all too familiar with those time-sapping repetitive tasks that take your attention away from the crux of your professional duties. Unfortunately, these simple yet monotonous chores are often unavoidable aspects of being a freelancer, from organising invoices each month to managing your emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the help of AI technology, you have the ability to automate some of these tasks that need doing on a regular basis, freeing up more of your time to focus on your primary output. For example, when it comes to invoices, AI can provide you with smart templates that can track your expenses, while also linking to time tracking tools to ensure you’re charging for your time accurately. In addition, some tools can help you to manage your inbox by automatically filtering out unhelpful emails, while also having the capacity to create content and suggest subject lines when writing your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creative-inspiration&quot;&gt;Creative inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re a copywriter, graphic designer or any other kind of creative freelancer, running out of ideas can be a major barrier to productivity. With the ability to analyse data and patterns, AI can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/benjaminlaker/2022/08/24/how-leaders-are-using-ai-as-a-problem-solving-tool/&quot;&gt;enhance problem-solving capabilities&lt;/a&gt; by helping freelancers identify new and creative solutions that they might not be able to see themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, certain tools can be used to generate ideas for blogs, designs or just about any other kind of creative digital outlet. By making the most of AI, you too will be able to unlock your full creative potential, even on the days where imagination is harder to come by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time-management&quot;&gt;Time management&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to time management, it can be most effective to combine human influence with the use of AI to ensure you’re optimising your time as best you can. For example, you may already &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jam.co.uk/call-handling-services/&quot;&gt;utilise the services of a call handler&lt;/a&gt; or virtual assistant so you never miss out on an opportunity for work. But alongside this human element, you could consider using planning and scheduling tools that can automatically accept or divert calls/messages depending on whether or not the correspondence is during your working hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can integrate smart AI technologies into your digital calendar to help you prioritise your time effectively and automatically reschedule any conflicts to streamline your workflow and maximise your opportunity for work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-a-headstart-with-ai&quot;&gt;Get a headstart with AI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter which industry you specialise in, it’s clear that AI could have a part to play in helping you to maximise your potential and income as a freelancer. Test out some of these tools for yourself and see how you could streamline your workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cover photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@windows?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/MYomVPpR5FU?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/ai-tools-for-freelancers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/ai-tools-for-freelancers/</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>UI vs UX: Are They The Same Or Different, And What Is Their Impact On A Website?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The phrases ‘User Interface’ (UI) and ‘User Experience’ (UX) are frequently used in tech-related settings. What does a UX or UI design mean, and what is its impact on your web app or website?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When using a website, app, or electronic device, you interact with screens, buttons, toggles, icons, and other visual elements, referred to as user interfaces (UI). UX describes your overall experience using a product, including your feelings during that experience. Although UI can undoubtedly influence UX, the two are separate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog, we will examine the similarities and differences between UI and UX and their role in making a digital product worth its price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, without further ado, let us get into the details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-ux-design&quot;&gt;What is UX Design?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The user’s experience when interacting with a product or service is called the user experience (UX). UX design is a process that involves many various aspects of product development, such as branding, usability, function, and design, to create goods or services that offer meaningful user experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the entire procedure or journey a user goes through while interacting with a product or service as one method to approach user experience design. Whether through blogs, advertisements, or another method, how is the service or product introduced to the user? In what ways does the user interact with the brand? After the interaction, how does the user feel? Critical factors in UX design include all of these and more inquiries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main objective of a UX designer is for every user to interact positively with a good or service but there are many &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.esparkinfo.com/blog/top-ux-design-challenges-and-solutions.html&quot;&gt;UX design challenges&lt;/a&gt;  faced by designers and how they can solve them to deliver good user experience. The user should feel satisfied with the engagement, whether it gives pleasure, a solution to an issue, or assistance in locating important information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-ui-design&quot;&gt;What is UI Design?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrarily, UI design relates to the actual user interfaces that users interact with. Interactive elements such as sliders, text, photos, buttons, or widgets are used in the UI designs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UI designers ensure that each visual component, transition, and animation used in a product or service lays the groundwork for a smooth, satisfying experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;key-differences-between-ui-and-ux-design&quot;&gt;Key Differences Between UI and UX Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although UX and UI reflect different aspects of a product’s or service’s design, UI and UX sometimes must be clarified since they both collaborate closely. The two roles share some significant distinctions to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of their most prominent differences include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-look-versus-feel&quot;&gt;1. Look versus Feel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Product development involves both UI and UX design, which have different but connected functions. A product’s appearance, namely the interactive and visual features that enhance the user experience, is a component of UI design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, UX design is concerned with the overall aesthetics of a product or service and the elements that will help consumers have a valuable, pertinent experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-prototyping-versus-design&quot;&gt;2. Prototyping versus Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although they work on the same project, UX and UI designers have different roles and goals. UX designers usually build wireframes and test prototypes that form the basis of a website’s or service’s user flow. While UI designers create products and designs that stimulate user engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-in-depth-versus-high-level&quot;&gt;3. In-depth versus High-level&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The level of detail that goes into each designer’s work is another distinction between UI and UX designers. UI designers work on individual pages, buttons, and interactions to ensure their functionality and polish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UX designers ensure that the overall user flow of a website, service, or app is wholly realized and consistent by taking a higher-level perspective on a product or service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-the-connection-between-ui-and-ux&quot;&gt;What is the Connection Between UI and UX?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UI designer would develop the steering wheel, dashboard, and any controls in the driver’s seat if we were to simulate the app development process as creating a car. The UX designer would also ensure that the customer has a beautiful and seamless driving experience from beginning to end. As you can see from that illustration, the UX aspect considers all product or service elements, not just the digital assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us take a look at a running shoe-selling app. The moment you click it, the software looks fantastic. The animation and vibrant colors are abundant, and the buttons resemble tiny sneakers. Great! What a lovely user interface!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the shopping cart is useless; it cannot calculate shipping costs or sales taxes; the website must send out confirmations of purchases or shipment estimates; and the item takes an eternity to arrive. That user experience could be better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, even if you have the most appealing and engaging landing page, it will only matter if your website functions correctly. On the other hand, you might have a better product with a quick shipment, simple access to customer care, and frequently asked questions. However, the user is still forced to endure poor visuals and annoying sound effects. That won’t help you attract clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;combining-ui-and-ux-designs-the-process&quot;&gt;Combining UI and UX Designs: The Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire process of designing a site or application for usability involves UX and UI, even if their roles differ. Together, these fields of work contribute in a complimentary way to an enjoyable, straightforward user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A website or application’s UI design (i.e., the technical, aesthetically pleasing framework) serves as the foundation for the UX elements, such as the messaging and feel that clients experience. As a result, the total product or service benefits, and users are left with a lasting impression. Each professional’s efforts inform those of its counterpart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-is-it-crucial-to-understand-both-ux-and-ui&quot;&gt;Why is it Crucial to Understand Both UX and UI?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The complementary functions that UI and UX design play in web development make them naturally related. Professionals in either subject can contribute to a more transparent, integrated design process that results in a better, more usable final product by having a working knowledge of both concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who want to boost their employment prospects in various design-based positions can also benefit from such versatility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mainly, there is a huge demand for UX design expertise worldwide. The UX Design Institute reported that in 2021, 70% of managers expanded their design teams. Those wishing to take advantage of this increasing need can benefit from having a solid understanding of both UI and UX design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;impact-of-ui-and-ux-on-a-website&quot;&gt;Impact of UI and UX on a Website&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Layout, images, and user interactions are all tailored to the user’s needs and preferences when a website is designed with a user-centered approach. Here is where UI and UX are functional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By putting the user first, websites may offer an intuitive and seamless experience, making it easier for visitors to find the information they need, complete their jobs, and reach their objectives quickly. This user-centered method creates a positive perception of the brand, raises general user satisfaction, and encourages repurchasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excellent UI and UX design significantly impact user engagement and retention rates. A visually appealing and well-organized user interface draws users in, enticing them to explore and stay on the website longer. Users are encouraged to return and stick with the site because of its streamlined and straightforward user interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The effectiveness of the UI and UX design in interacting with users and fulfilling their expectations will ultimately determine the long-term viability of the website. This enhances user retention, lowers bounce rates, and increases user engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UI and UX of a website have a significant impact on its usability. Using a user-centered design strategy, websites may build smooth, intuitive experiences that appeal to users’ wants and preferences. A thoughtful UX design coupled with an aesthetically pleasing UI encourages user retention and boosts user engagement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UI and UX-focused websites foster long-term user loyalty and favorable brand perceptions. Ultimately, investing in UI and UX design is necessary to produce user-centered websites that leave a lasting impression on visitors, improve engagement, and guarantee the website’s ongoing success in the fiercely competitive digital market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/ui-vs-ux-are-they-the-same/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/ui-vs-ux-are-they-the-same/</guid>
        
        
        <category>marketing-tips</category>
        
        <category>freelancing</category>
        
        <category>general</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Get Your Creative Business on the Map</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a creative professional, obviously you want to get your work out there. Often, though, that’s easier said than done. The key to success is having a plan and taking the necessary steps to ensure that your work is visible and accessible. So here are some tips on how creators just like you can get their work on the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;preparing-your-portfolio&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preparing Your Portfolio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having an impressive portfolio is essential for any creative professional looking to get their work noticed. Make sure that your portfolio &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cca.edu/newsroom/six-things-your-art-portfolio-must-have/&quot;&gt;includes your best work&lt;/a&gt; and showcases the range of skills that you possess. If possible, include images or videos of previous projects so potential employers can get an idea of what you can do before even meeting you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great way to show off your skills is by using 3D texture painting to include eye-catching images. In fact, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adobe.com/products/substance3d-painter.html&quot;&gt;this could help&lt;/a&gt; your work get noticed and generate more buzz around your business. These kinds of images are also great for sharing via social media or adding to your own personal website, further expanding your potential customer base. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-a-business-plan&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing a Business Plan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When creating a business plan, it’s important to be thorough and detail-oriented. Include information about yourself and what services and products you offer, how much money you need for start-up costs, and where potential customers may come from. Having &lt;a href=&quot;https://superfine.world/blog-content/2019/12/9/business-plans-for-artists-what-every-artist-should-know&quot;&gt;a well-crafted business plan&lt;/a&gt; will give investors confidence when considering investing in your creativity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;locating-investors&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Locating Investors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of investors, you need to find investors who are interested in what you have to offer to get your work out there. Research potential investors and &lt;a href=&quot;https://visible.vc/blog/startup-funding-proposal-sample/&quot;&gt;reach out with a detailed proposal&lt;/a&gt; outlining why they should invest in you. Make sure to include relevant information such as past projects, awards, or any other accolades that will help prove your worthiness as an investment, as well as show off your portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;showcasing-your-work&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Showcasing Your Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting your work noticed doesn’t have to be expensive or time-consuming. Look for opportunities like &lt;a href=&quot;https://thepracticalartworld.com/2021/06/28/approaching-a-gallery-the-initial-email-an-example-of-what-to-send/&quot;&gt;art shows or gallery openings&lt;/a&gt; to display your work without spending too much money on advertising or marketing campaigns. Put your work out there in local newspapers, magazines, or websites, and remember to network with other creatives. Additionally, if you’re a web designer or graphic designer, take advantage of online platforms to showcase your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;building-a-network&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building a Network&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The creative industry is all about networking, so it’s important to build relationships with other creatives to get your work noticed. Attending events is crucial. Additionally, many cities offer free spaces for creatives, such as libraries or parks &lt;a href=&quot;https://veryprivategallery.com/show-your-art/&quot;&gt;where artwork can be displayed publicly&lt;/a&gt;, so take advantage of these resources, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a creative person looking to connect with others in the field, designing business cards can be an invaluable tool when it comes to networking. It is a great way to share contact information and make sure people remember who you are. Additionally, making sure &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thebalancemoney.com/effective-business-card-2951735&quot;&gt;your card accurately conveys&lt;/a&gt; not just your contact details but also gives the recipient insight into who you are, what values you bring to the table, and what services you offer can help build strong relationships that lead to meaningful collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;registering-your-business&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Registering Your Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Registering as an LLC or Limited Liability Company provides protection against personal liability should anything happen as you conduct business activities. It also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dummies.com/business/start-a-business/small-business-financing/structuring-your-llc-to-attract-investors/&quot;&gt;gives you more credibility&lt;/a&gt;, which could help attract more clients and investors, as they know that they’re dealing with someone who has taken the extra step of registering their business legally and, therefore, takes their venture seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you decide to work from home, it’s a good idea to set aside a designed workspace or office. If doing so requires some renovation – like converting a garage, finishing a basement, or expanding a smaller room to give you more space and natural light – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.redfin.com/guides/how-to-increase-your-home-appraisal-value-now&quot;&gt;make sure you save those receipts&lt;/a&gt;, since certain home improvements have the added benefit of raising your home’s value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By following the above tips, creators can take their first steps toward getting their work out there and into the public eye as a legitimate business – all without breaking the bank or wasting too much time trying to figure things out on their own. Taking advantage of available resources, creating quality business cards, and registering as an LLC are just some ways you can make sure your talents are seen by potential clients and investors. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pexels.com/photo/woman-singing-on-stage-1460037/&quot;&gt;Pexels&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/get-your-creative-business-on-the-map/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/get-your-creative-business-on-the-map/</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Write Compelling Email Copy that Converts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2022 alone, there were a total of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.statista.com/statistics/456500/daily-number-of-e-mails-worldwide/&quot;&gt;333.2 billion&lt;/a&gt; emails sent out and received globally. Sounds outrageously high? That is now the reality in our increasingly digitalized world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that huge amount of emails that people receive, how do you make sure that your email actually gets read and seen? The answer is to write a great and captivating email copy that can grab your audience’s eye. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why we wrote this guide for you on how to write your emails to make them pop, and make sure it doesn’t get buried under all the other emails in your audience’s inbox. Read on to find out more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-tips-on-how-to-write-compelling-email-copy&quot;&gt;1. Tips on how to write compelling email copy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After building your email list and looking for an email automation tool to use, you are now at the hardest part of email marketing — creating the email itself. It’s not an exaggeration to say that your email’s success will greatly depend on its copy. It’s what determines if people will click on your email in the first place. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-write-conversationally&quot;&gt;2. Write conversationally&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are in a digital era where social media is king. Because of this, brands and businesses feel more at reach than ever before. People view them now as friends or equals, instead of a higher authority. Which is why if you want your emails to convert, you need to write more conversationally and casually. No one wants to read an email full of corporate jargon. If you address your audience like a friend, they’ll more likely read your emails. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do you write conversationally? First, stick to plain language. Avoid jargon and overly-flowery words. Second, write shorter sentences. When you text your friends, you don’t really text them in full paragraphs, right? And speaking of your friends, just get into that mindset when you’re writing your emails. Try to use a more informal and relaxed language in your emails, just like how you would when you’re having a conversation with them. You can even add humor to your emails, so long as you still remain professional. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some examples: change “Greetings” to “Hey there”, change “Tickets are available for purchase now” to “Save your spot now!”, change “Our product is rated to be a high-quality product, according to these reviews we gathered” to “Not to brag, but our product is pretty awesome. Check out these reviews!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See? Some simple changes can change up the vibe of your messages. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-make-them-personalized&quot;&gt;3. Make them personalized&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sending personalized emails is also important. While everyone knows that brands send emails in bulk, your audience still wants to feel special. After all, no one wants to read emails that feel like it was just sent to the void, that it doesn’t matter who reads it. A little VIP treatment might just be the boost you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the easiest ways to do this is to address your audience by their first name. According to studies, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.experianplc.com/media/latest-news/2014/experian-marketing-services-study-finds-personalized-emails-generate-six/&quot;&gt;29%&lt;/a&gt; of people are more likely to open emails if their name is used. With the advancements of email marketing tools, it’s now easy to get your subscriber’s name, so there’s no excuse to not do this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another is to segment your emails. With email marketing tools, you can send specific emails based on different categories or criteria. This could be based on their location, gender, browsing data, actions they’ve taken on your website, etc. This means your audience can receive emails that are personalized to them or their interests, so it’s more likely that they’ll be more engaged with your messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, your audience has added running shoes to his cart on your website. You can set a reminder email for him that he hasn’t checked-out the item yet. Or perhaps send him a “We think you might like this…” email, where you recommend him a track pants or gym bag to go along with his running shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from sending well-timed messages, data can also be used to personalize the language in your emails. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the data you’ve gathered, you can adjust your email’s language to one that your target audience will respond more to. For example, instead of just sending out a promotional email like “We have a new Productivity Book available in our store”, you can switch it to “We think this book can help you achieve your goals, so we set aside a copy for you. Get it here!”. The second one is definitely more personal and inviting, right? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-have-great-subject-lines&quot;&gt;4. Have great subject lines&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, subject lines. It’s truly the make or break part of emails, as most people don’t even view your message if you don’t get their attention from the start. You don’t want to waste your awesome email by having a bland subject line that people will just scroll over. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do you write a good one? First, keep it short and sweet. Use no more than 9 words or 60 characters. Second, make it clear from the subject what the email is about. While a little mystery might be good from time to time, generally, people want to know what the email is about before they click on it. For example, if their subscription is expiring, send them a subject line like “Hey [name], time to renew your subscription” instead of something vague like “Changes are needed in your account”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, use action-oriented words. This makes your email feel more exciting and adds a sense of urgency to it. Fourth, make it as compelling as possible. Pose interesting questions, or tell them a very powerful benefit they can get from your email. For example, “Are you making these 5 new baker mistakes?”, or “Here’s a tip to increase your sales by 60%”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-add-emojis&quot;&gt;5. Add emojis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of subject lines, another way to make it more engaging is to add emojis. According to a study by Experian, 56% of businesses have seen an increase in open rates when they’ve used emojis. So why not try to add some in your emails too?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some things to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t overuse it. Use one or two at most in your subject lines.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t use it in every single subject line of yours. Your audience will get tired of it fast!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Only use it when it makes sense. If you are a formal B2B business, your audience probably won’t appreciate emojis. But if you are catered to a younger Gen-Z audience, then use them by all means. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Test out different ones. Some emojis might work better than others. Experiment to see what works best for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The most commonly used emoji is the red heart. You can use the same one to fit in with others, or you try less used emojis to stand out. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;6-use-marketing-psychology&quot;&gt;6. Use marketing psychology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employing various marketing psychology tactics can also help in making your email more compelling. Some examples are FOMO and using social proof. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FOMO, or the Fear Of Missing Out, is one of the biggest tactics to invoke a sense of urgency. Using lines like “Limited Time Only”, “Stock is running out!”, “All your friends are already using this…” can make your products look more in-demand, and can also cause people to click on your email since they want to get the deals while it’s still available. Implying that lots of people are already using the product is also effective, since people always want to be “in the know” and don’t want to miss out on the trends. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social proof, on the other hand, is the use of customer reviews as proof that your product is well-liked. You can add snippets of 5 star customer reviews on your email body, or mention it in your subject line. This is effective because people tend to trust reviews more than they trust promotional content from a brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;7-dont-forget-your-visuals&quot;&gt;7. Don’t forget your visuals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the copy and text is important, having great visuals is also crucial. Make sure to use appealing and high-quality images, whether you use photography or graphic art on your emails. Don’t forget your branding - stick to your brand’s color scheme and typography, and always add your logo. If you don’t have a logo yet, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brandcrowd.com/logo-maker&quot;&gt;logo maker&lt;/a&gt; tools online to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure to stick to a clean and easily readable layout. Your text should be aligned in the center. See if there is good contrast between the background color and your text. Also, check if your emails are mobile-friendly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;8-wrapping-up&quot;&gt;8. Wrapping Up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your email copy plays a huge part in the success of your email marketing campaigns. Carefully consider the language and tone of your emails, send them to the correct person at the right time, match it with eye-catching visuals, and make sure to always proofread. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With our tips, you’ll be improving your email’s conversion rate for sure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors-bio&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author’s Bio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Janella Malapad&lt;/em&gt; - Janella is an outreach specialist at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.designcrowd.com/&quot;&gt;DesignCrowd&lt;/a&gt;, your go-to online creative hub for logo design, website design contests, and an array of imaginative graphic design possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-write-email-copy-that-converts/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-write-email-copy-that-converts/</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Running A Business &amp; Having a Life</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Running a business brings many challenges, and so does running a household. While the two aren’t mutually exclusive, keeping all aspects of your life operating smoothly requires some organization and planning. Todaywe have some tips to help you manage the many facets of your life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set priorities and boundaries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/swlh/work-life-balance-can-it-exist-for-entrepreneurs-18b5e10e4623&quot;&gt;establish what your priorities are&lt;/a&gt;, so make a list of them. Determine what is essential, what would be nice, and what can be put aside, at least for now. Once you are clear on the things that are most important, develop a schedule for attending to them. You may not have to do every single thing yourself–accepting help is a strength. You’ll need to set boundaries to make sure your time and energy are going to the things that are most important to you. You may need to put exercise or time with friends on your calendar to prevent brushing them aside. Setting and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thehartford.com/business-insurance/strategy/infographics/work-life-balance&quot;&gt;sticking with regular work hours&lt;/a&gt; can be very helpful. Learning to say no is important in business as well as social and home life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delegate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although many entrepreneurs like being hands-on with all aspects of the business, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lifehack.org/688325/how-to-delegate-work-the-definitive-guide-for-successful-leaders&quot;&gt;nobody can truly do it all&lt;/a&gt;. It’s important to distinguish the things that must be done &lt;em&gt;by you&lt;/em&gt;, from the things that can be delegated. You may find that you can hire freelancers to take on certain tasks at your business, particularly during the busier seasons. You might use a virtual assistant at work to automate emails to customers, social media postings, and other routine tasks. Sometimes hiring a professional for specific endeavors can save you a lot of time and money. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, if you have decided to make your business a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shopify.com/blog/llc-advantages&quot;&gt;limited liability company&lt;/a&gt; (LLC), which has tax benefits as well as protects your assets, you could hire an attorney to do the legwork. Since each state has different regulations for LLCs, you might want to work with an online formation service that’s already familiar with the specific regulations and can get you started in minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delegate at home, too&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may also find it helpful to delegate some of the responsibilities associated with your home life. One can &lt;a href=&quot;https://motherhoodsimplified.com/how-to-delegate-in-the-home/&quot;&gt;often find freelancers&lt;/a&gt; to do tasks including cleaning, pet care, child care, and running errands. Don’t overlook the value of asking other household members to help, too. Kids and teens can help fold and put away laundry, take out the trash, and help with simple tasks like sweeping and loading the dishwasher. If you lack time to go to the gym, you might benefit from an online exercise coach or class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manage your documents&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your business needs a good document management system. At some point, most businesses will need to share documents with staff, suppliers, or clients. In many instances, PDFs are the preferred format for such documents. Although some work may have been created as image files, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adobe.com/acrobat/hub/how-to/how-to-convert-png-to-pdf&quot;&gt;the best solution&lt;/a&gt; is to use this free tool to convert them to PDFs, saving you lots of time and hassle. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although nobody would claim that running a business and running a household simultaneously is easy, it can be done with adequate help. It’s important to acknowledge your own limitations and honor them rather than overextending yourself and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.terriklassconsulting.com/2021/07/25/juggling-leadership-responsibilities-to-avoid-burnout/&quot;&gt;getting burned out&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Set your priorities, and schedule them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to include time with your family, friends, pets, and hobbies, as well as exercise and adequate sleep if these are important to you. Delegate, ask for help, and learn to say no to things that don’t support your goals and priorities. Remember to schedule some slow time or rest time, too–none of us can operate at full speed indefinitely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article Courtesy of Adam Taylor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Adam Taylor is committed to separating work and home so that he can enjoy both. Now, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://TaylorandNoel.com&quot;&gt;TaylorandNoel.com&lt;/a&gt;, he’s sharing his best practices with other freelancers, in hopes they can do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/running-a-business-having-a-life/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/running-a-business-having-a-life/</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Legal Issues Every Freelancer Should Know About</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Freelancers may work as subcontractors, independent contractors, or gig workers under the term “freelancer.” Under the law, freelancers are treated as business owners rather than employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike other workers, you are not subject to the laws governing employment. You operate like a small business; generally, the law treats you that way. You can take on multiple clients without worrying about employee benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.optnation.com/blog/top-professions-suitable-for-freelancing-jobs/&quot;&gt;running a freelance business&lt;/a&gt;, it’s crucial to understand how the law affects your ability to operate legally. You must understand what the law is and how it affects your freelancing. This will help ensure that you don’t encounter any problems with tax or contract issues that could cause trouble for your freelancing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;legal-issues-to-consider-for-every-freelancer&quot;&gt;Legal Issues to Consider for Every Freelancer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may not have the resources of a larger company to handle legal matters, but it’s important to know the basics of what every freelancer should know about legal issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the most important things every freelancer should know about legal issues and what they mean for your business:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;form-an-llc&quot;&gt;Form an LLC&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although you can run your freelance business as a sole proprietorship, it is usually better to form a limited liability company with one member. Most importantly, a limited liability company reduces the risk of business debts being paid with personal assets. Depending on your circumstances, the S-Corp tax election may reduce your taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LLCs are also better business structures for freelancers. An LLC lets you add owners, get an EIN, open a business bank account, and better track business expenses. Finally, potential customers view LLCs as more credible. Get help from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smrlaw.net/&quot;&gt;business lawyer&lt;/a&gt; if you need help forming an LLC. As a freelancer, you may think that legal issues are only for big businesses, but that’s not true. Even freelancers need to know about legal matters — especially if they want to stay in business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business lawyers are experts in their field, and they can quickly help you form an LLC. They can also advise what steps to take after starting your company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pay-taxes&quot;&gt;Pay Taxes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freelancers are responsible for fulfilling their tax responsibilities. This indicates that the federal government, state governments, and local governments will look to you to pay your income taxes, taxes for social security and Medicare, taxes for local governments, and other taxes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting aside thirty percent of your net income for taxes is generally recommended. You should pay estimated taxes quarterly and prepare to make additional payments at tax time if you owe more than you paid last year. The most effective way to handle this administrative work is to talk to an accountant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;contracts-and-agreements&quot;&gt;Contracts and Agreements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you start working for clients in any capacity, you must have some kind of contract or agreement between yourself and them. This could be anything from an invoice for work to a non-disclosure agreement (NDA). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good contract will protect both parties from misunderstandings or disagreements in the future; it should clearly state what each party expects from the other party, how payments are made and when they are due, what happens if one party fails to do what they agreed upon, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;contracts-with-subcontractors&quot;&gt;Contracts with Subcontractors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure all your subcontractors have written contracts. In hiring a subcontractor, you will make a contract with a format similar to the agreements you make with clients, but they are undoubtedly written differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intellectual property provisions should be included in the subcontractor agreement template you use. Make sure your template states that you own the work product created by the subcontractor (and all associated IP). Otherwise, the subcontractor may claim ownership of all that work. You won’t be able to pass ownership on to your clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;insurance&quot;&gt;Insurance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must be insured. If you live in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/advisor/health-insurance/do-you-have-to-have-health-insurance/#&quot;&gt;state with individual mandates&lt;/a&gt; for residents, you must have health insurance or pay the penalty. If you’re an independent contractor and don’t have an employer-sponsored plan, you can buy insurance on your own through the exchanges set up by the Affordable Care Act (ACA). Otherwise, you can purchase individual coverage from an insurer participating in the ACA’s small business exchange or through Healthcare.gov.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;termination-rights&quot;&gt;Termination Rights&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When freelancers work for clients or other businesses, they often sign contracts that specify the contract’s duration, rights to terminate the contract early, and penalties if the contract is terminated by one party, not the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you agree with someone paying you for your services, you must know what your rights are in case anything goes wrong. Clarify the terms and ensure that you and the clients are on the same page regarding the specifics. If there are disagreements later, the contract will serve as a point of reference for both of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the contract should serve as a warning sign. You should not engage in commercial transactions with a customer unwilling to sign a contract or attempting to negotiate terms that heavily favor their requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freelancing is an excellent way to earn money on your own schedule. You get to set your own hours and pick and choose projects that interest you. However, it can also be a very challenging lifestyle without the right protections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a freelancer, the law will only protect you if you take the necessary steps to protect yourself in the first place. To avoid being on the losing end of a legal dispute, do some research and speak with a lawyer about potential issues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/legal-issues-every-freelancer-should-know-about/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/legal-issues-every-freelancer-should-know-about/</guid>
        
        
        <category>general</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Become a Freelance Writer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Writing is a skill that doesn’t come easy to everyone, but if it’s something you do well and enjoy then you should consider potential writing careers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working as a freelance writer is a great way to earn some extra money and improve your craft. It’s a very flexible option with plenty of opportunities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;increase-your-income-ceiling&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increase Your Income Ceiling&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your income ceiling is a metaphorical barrier you hit when you are no longer able to earn more money based on the work you’re doing. For example, if you’re a photographer you can only handle so many clients at a time. In order to make more money, you either need to raise your prices or hire more help so you can take on more clients. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With freelancing, you get to increase how much you’re able to earn. You have more control over the work you’re able to do and you can take on as many clients as you can. If you have another job, then &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crowdcontent.com/blog/writers-hub/9-benefits-of-freelance-writing-as-told-by-top-content-writers/&quot;&gt;working as a freelancer&lt;/a&gt; only adds to the income you’re making. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;start-your-own-retirement-plan&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start Your Own Retirement Plan&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone should begin saving for retirement as early as they can. This gives you more time to save up for retirement. As a freelancer, you have a lot of options when it comes to starting a retirement account. You get to choose the plan that works best for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.planperfectretirement.com/sep-vs-401k/&quot;&gt;SEP-IRAs are ideal&lt;/a&gt; choices for self-employed people due to their simplicity. They have high contribution limits, don’t require contributions each year, and are extremely flexible. Other plan options include traditional and Roth IRA plans, Solo 401(k) accounts, and a simple IRA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-flexibility&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More Flexibility&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main benefits of being a freelance writer is you have more control over your career and what work you do. You get to choose what projects you work on. You choose where you work from. You’re in control of how much you work at a time. You aren’t beholden to anyone else’s schedule (aside from the needs of your clients). &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.crowdcontent.com/blog/writers-hub/9-benefits-of-freelance-writing-as-told-by-top-content-writers/&quot;&gt;As a freelancer&lt;/a&gt;, it’s easier to have a work-life balance and you don’t need to feel overwhelmed by work. Everything is on your terms. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If writing is something you want to pursue, then you should look into freelance work. You can improve your writing skills, explore new kinds of writing, and earn some extra money. It’s worth it to learn more about being a freelance writer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did you enjoy reading this article? Here’s more to read. Ready to start your consulting business? Grab my&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.katebagoy.com/ebook&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;book&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;to get started today&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-become-a-freelance-writer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-become-a-freelance-writer/</guid>
        
        
        <category>freelancing</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Get Out and Promote Your Brand</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As a small business owner, it’s important to get out and promote your brand. You can’t just sit behind your computer all day and expect people to find you. To be successful, you need to put yourself out there and reach new customers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some tips for getting out and promoting your brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;attend-networking-conferences&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attend Networking Conferences&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://insights.q4intel.com/use-networking-conferences-to-build-your-business/&quot;&gt;Attending networking conferences&lt;/a&gt; is a great way to get out and promote your brand. Not only can you learn about cutting-edge business practices, but you can also connect with potential customers and partners in the same industry. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking part in different conversations will give you a valuable chance to make yourself known, share your ideas, and build important relationships that could potentially lead to new opportunities. Plus, some of these venues provide workshops and other events that could inspire creativity and spark new directions for your business. Taking the time to attend a few select networking conferences could be an incredible way to generate buzz around your brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;speak-at-an-event&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speak at an Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Promoting your brand is one of the most important ways to jump-start your success and start getting noticed. If you’re looking for a creative way to do that, consider speaking at an event. You’ll be able to share your expertise with a group of people who might just need help. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should &lt;a href=&quot;https://josephsmithmemorialbuildingmeetingsandevents.com/factors-to-consider-when-booking-a-private-event-space/&quot;&gt;make sure the venue has the technology&lt;/a&gt; you need to present before you start speaking. You should check for things like microphones and presentation screens, as well as wifi connection and cordless clickers. Making sure these are all in place before you start speaking will help keep you organized while showcasing your best qualities!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-a-pop-up&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do a Pop-Up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.shopify.com/blog/pop-up-shop&quot;&gt;Organizing a pop-up&lt;/a&gt; is an incredibly effective way to promote your brand, allowing you to directly engage with customers and share your story. This tactic can truly help take your business to the next level, as customer face-to-face interaction creates a strong connection with potential buyers and allows them to experience your brand firsthand in an engaging, creative setting. Whether you’re selling products or services, a pop-up provides a unique opportunity for you to make meaningful connections with customers and leave them feeling inspired by what you have to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to develop your brand and engage customers, you need to get out into the world. There are endless possibilities to go grow your brand. Try these tips or give your ideas a try to promote your brand. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Did you enjoy reading this article? Here’s more to read. Ready to start your consulting business? Grab my&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ebook.katebagoy.com/lto&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;book&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;to get started today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-get-out-and-promote-your-brand/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-get-out-and-promote-your-brand/</guid>
        
        
        <category>marketing-tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Benefits of Working as a Freelancer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Freelance work has become more popular, but for many people, it can still be an unfamiliar idea. While there are a lot of upsides to working as a normal employee, there are some benefits that come from being a freelancer that you aren’t going to find in a normal job that can make up for some of the stress that comes from working freelance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;create-your-own-schedule&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create Your Own Schedule&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a freelancer, you are answerable only to yourself and the deadlines that you set when scheduling your projects with your clients. This allows you &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.xolo.io/how-to-create-an-optimal-work-schedule-as-a-freelancer&quot;&gt;to set your own schedule&lt;/a&gt; and work at whatever time works best for you. Some people find they are more productive at different times of day, so experiment with different schedules to see what works best for you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also take a break if you need to relax or run errands, without worrying that your boss will notice that you aren’t at work. It is important to actually set aside time to work though. If you don’t, you run the risk of putting it off until the last minute and either missing deadlines or rushing the job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;reduce-your-taxes&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduce Your Taxes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a self-employed freelancer, you are required to file taxes as a business owner in order to stay on the right side of the IRS. However, there are things that you can do to reduce the amount of taxes that you have to pay. Keep track of what you are paying for and using for your business. For instance, if you have to drive to meet with clients, you can deduct some of those costs as a business expense. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also invest some of your income in your own retirement accounts. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.planperfectretirement.com/sep-vs-401k/&quot;&gt;SEP-IRA lets you make tax-deductible contributions&lt;/a&gt; of 20% of your net income. Because of the deductions you are able to make, you are likely to end up paying fewer taxes than a normal employee who makes the same gross amount as you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;enjoy-your-work&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enjoy Your Work&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest struggles that people have with work is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tomedes.com/translator-hub/being-freelancer-makes-you-happier-person.php&quot;&gt;figuring out how to enjoy&lt;/a&gt; what they are spending their time doing. However, if you are freelancing, that means you get to choose what you are doing, which allows you to turn your passions into your career. This doesn’t mean it is easy by any stretch of the imagination, but it does mean that you are unlikely to hate your job or feel uninspired. This is one of the biggest benefits of working freelance. Combined with the ability to set your own schedule, you can easily find a way to live a life that you love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to these benefits, working as a freelancer opens up your earning potential to anything you are willing to work for. It takes hard work and a lot of dedication, but there is always a way to be successful at what you love doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ready to start your consulting business? Grab my&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://ebook.katebagoy.com/lto&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;book&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;to get started today.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-benefits-of-working-as-a-freelancer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-benefits-of-working-as-a-freelancer/</guid>
        
        
        <category>freelancing</category>
        
        <category>general</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
